rollcall.com 2015-09-21

# Privacy | Economist Group

## **The Economist Group's privacy policy**

The Economist Group is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers. Because we operate from offices around the world, we have taken steps to ensure that high standards of data protection are adhered to globally for all the forms of data processing mentioned below. This statement outlines our privacy and data protection policy.

### **Definitions**  

"The Economist Group" comprises The Economist Newspaper Limited and its subsidiaries, which together operate a number of businesses, including the following:

  * The Economist
  * Other Economist-branded businesses, such as Economist Intelligence Unit, Economist Events and Economist Corporate Network
  * CQ-Roll Call Group (including Capitol Advantage, Congressional Quarterly and Roll Call)
  * Bazian
  * Clearstate
  * EuroFinance Conferences
  * TVC Group
  * Learningly
  * Ideas People Media

A "customer" (or "you") is anyone ordering, registering for or making use of any product, service or website of any Economist Group business.

### **Collection and use of customer information**

Your personal details are collected and processed when you order, purchase, register, subscribe or make use of any of our products or services. Information is collected by the companies of The Economist Group. For our businesses operated in the EU and EEA, the companies listed at the end of this policy statement are each registered with the United Kingdom's Information Commissioner's Office as a data controller in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

In addition, when you visit any of our websites or use any of our digital applications (such as our iPhone or iPad applications), we also collect website and application usage information (which may include your reading history and any advertisements you may have viewed), and information about your computer or other digital device and your internet connection. This includes your computer's or digital device’s IP address, the type and version of browser and operating system you use, your internet domain and, if you visited via a link from another website, the URL of the linking page.

The information we collect from you is meant to help us:

  * fulfil your order
  * manage your registration preferences
  * send you renewal notifications and/or service notifications
  * personalise web content and advertising based on your personal characteristics or preferences
  * ensure, as far as is practical, that our websites and applications are compatible with the browsers and operating systems used by most of our visitors
  * conduct customer satisfaction surveys

And, if you allow us to*, we may also:

  * tell you about additional products and services
  * tell you about other promotional activities across The Economist Group of companies or other companies with whom we have a business relationship
  * invite you to participate in market research, surveys and polls for ourselves or for our clients

*Please indicate your privacy preferences using the order, registration or subscription form when ordering, purchasing, registering or subscribing.

We also use your information for in-house research and analysis. This helps us to:

  * improve our understanding of customer needs
  * create marketing profiles
  * support strategic development
  * To enable us to conduct research we may share your information with third party suppliers employed to help, if compelled to do so by law, or with other third parties if you give your specific consent, such as in the case of a complaint. All results of any research and analysis will be anonymised or aggregated information and will not reveal any personal details of individual customers.

Other than as expressly set out in this policy, we do not use any of your personally identifiable information (which is any information that identifies you or can be used to identify you) for advertising, and nor do we track or collect it other than as stated above so that we can provide you with our products or services. We also do not track or collect any of your sensitive information which includes information such as your race, religion, ethnicity, and political opinion. Please note however that the collection, use, and disclosure of information by our business partners are described in their own privacy policies, and consequently may differ from The Economist Group’s Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for those third party privacy policies and you should ensure that you have read and accept all applicable privacy policies before proceeding.

### **Ideas People Media**

Ideas People Media (IPM) is part of The Economist Group, and is a digital advertising network that may deliver advertisements to pre-selected partners that address an audience of like-minded _The Economist_ readers. We deliver advertising to this audience in part by targeting them based on their interests and browsing behavior.

Whenever we deliver these ads to you in the United States, Canada and the European Union, we will mark them with the AdChoice icon so that you can have full visibility on which ad is tracking your behavior online and apply your right to opt-out from such tracking through the icon. We do not, however, control the privacy policies of the partner sites that belong to our network and it is your responsibility to become informed about the privacy practices of the websites you visit. Please see the Cookies section below and our cookie policy [here](http://www.economist.com/cookies-info) for more information.

### **Cookies**

A cookie is a small file which is placed on your hard drive when you visit any of the Group's websites (directly or via our applications). We use information from cookies for purposes which may include:

  * identifying returning users, registrants and subscribers
  * eliminating the need for returning users to re-enter their login details
  * enabling you to move more easily around our sites and applications
  * tracking your use of our sites to better develop our sites and applications in accordance with your requirements
  * building up an anonymous profile based on your browsing patterns across our sites, applications and third party websites, which enables us to make advertisements and content available to you that is more relevant to your interests

You can find more information about our cookie policy [here](http://www.economist.com/cookies-info). 

### **E-mails**

The Economist Group uses reputable third parties to deliver the e-mails you receive if you have subscribed to e-mail newsletters, or have chosen to receive information about Economist Group products, services and offers. These third parties use unique identifiers and invisible images (often called "pixel tags" or "clear GIFs") to perform message open sensing, message format sensing, and click-through sensing in order to bring you more relevant information.

To find out more about the technologies used in these e-mails sent on our behalf, please visit <http://www.sailthru.com/legal/#privacy>. Content and some ad services in these e-mails are provided by Economist Group servers or by a third party.

### **External links**

Our websites may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. The Economist Group is not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites and we recommend that you read the privacy policies on any external sites you use.

### **Transfer of personal data overseas**

As the internet is a global environment, collecting and processing personal information may involve the transmission of this data internationally, including outside of the European Union. Therefore, by communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to your personal data being processed in this way.

### **Individuals under 16**

The Economist Group does not intentionally or knowingly process personal information from individuals under the age of 16. When necessary, underage users will be told not to submit any personal details and we will make every effort to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has informed us that these details or applicable data as defined by law have been collected.

### **Changes to this statement**

From time to time, we may make changes to the privacy policy. This may be in relation to changes in the law, best practice or changes in our services. These changes will be reflected in this statement, so you should check here from time to time.

### **Companies**

In accordance with the UK Data Protection Act 1998, the following companies are registered with the United Kingdom's Information Commissioner's Office as a data controller to collect information:

Data controller: The Economist Newspaper Limited   
Registered Office:  25 St James's Street, London SW1A 1HG, UK  
ICO Registered Number: Z7134617 Data Protection Registration Number: 236383  
Other names: The World In, The Economist, European Voice, Economist.com, Intelligent Life

Data controller:The Economist Intelligence Unit Limited  
Registered Office: 25 St James's Street, London SW1A 1HG, UK  
ICO Registered Number: Z6982453   
Data Protection Registration Number: 1762617  
Other names: EIU, Economist Intelligence Unit, Economist Conferences, Economist Corporate Network

Data controller: EuroFinance Conferences Ltd  
Registered Office: 25 St James's Street, London SW1A 1HG, UK  
ICO Registered Number: Z4865712  
Data Protection Registration Number: 3015764    
Other names: EuroFinance Intelligence, EuroFinance Training

### **How do you contact us?**

If you have questions about this policy or Ideas People Media, please send correspondence to us at the following address:

The Economist Group

Attn: Data Protection Officer

750 3rd Avenue

To relay any concern regarding the respect of your privacy, you may use this email address:

dataprotectionofficer@economist.com

You may also contact our consumer services via the following:

Telephone: 1 800 456 6086 (from outside the US and Canada, 1 636 449 5702)

Facsimile: 1 866 856 8075 (from outside the US and Canada, 1 636 449 5703)

E-mail: [customerhelp@economist.com](mailto:customerhelp@economist.com)

Last update—February 26th, 2015
